A Guide to the Robert Grant Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7634
Robert Grant Collection 1892-1925
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7634
17 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 17 Dec 1963 ] 26 Jul 1964
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Robert Grant to Samuel Sidney McClure, 1892 Jul 16; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sends 2 chapters of
    The Sixshooter
    sent to publisher.]
  - Robert Grant to Miss Farrell, 1892 Jul 16; ALS, 1 p.
    [Responds to request for autograph.]
  - Robert Grant to S. F. McCleary, 1893 Jul 12; ALS, 3 p.
    [Thanks him for congratulatory letter on Grant's appointment as Judge of Probate Court.]
  - Robert Grant to David Teller Fleisher, 1896 Oct 1; ANS, 1 p.
  - Robert Grant to [Charles] Scribner, 1900 Mar 6; ANS, 1 p.
    [Responds to suggestion for title of [
    Unleavened Bread
    ].]
  - Robert Grant to Mr. Johnson, 1904 Jun 10; ALS, 2 p.
    [Sends manuscript of
    The Orchid
    requests it be read promptly and response sent to Charles Scribner's Sons.]
  - Robert Grant to [Abbie Farwell] Brown, 1914 May 18; ALS, 2 p.
    [Comments on controversy concerning
    The Club
    and women's attitudes toward it.]
  - Robert Grant to Abbie Farwell Brown, 1914 Nov 10; TNS, 1 p.
    [Accepts invitation to a meeting.]
  - Robert Grant to [Abbie Farwell] Brown, [1915] Nov 4; ALS, 2 p.
    [Indicates intention to attend meeting.]
  - Robert Grant to Robert [Underwood] Johnson, 1923 May 17; TLS, 1 p.
    [Seeks guidance on how to respond to a request from Henri Corbiere of the Societe de Gens de Lettre de France for his "maxim of life."]
  - Robert Grant to [Abbie Farwell] Brown, 1925 Feb 11; ANS, 2 p.
    [Apologizes that illness prevented his attending her poetry reading.]
  - Robert Grant to Robley Durham Stevens, 1938 May 9; TLS, 1 p.
    [Responds to request for photograph.]
- Manuscripts
  - "Summary of the Remaining Chapters of Novel", ca. 1909; AMsS, 8 p.
    [
    The Chippendales
    . ]
  - "Change in Summary of Concluding Chapters", ca. 1904; AMs
  - Poem, " A Message ", n. d.; AMsS, 2 p.
    [Contributed to Edith Wharton's
    Book of the Homeless
  - Quotation beginning "Even as frost in the silent night ....", n. d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Quotation beginning, "Even as frost in the silent night.. .", n. d.; AMsS